홈 랜 드
한글자막 그레이
배포 DC 기미갤
어디 있는지 몰라도
찾아서 바꿔줘요
I don't care where he is.
Find him.
시간이 없어요
It's urgent.
기다릴게요
Yes, I'll hold.
He's been locked up
for almost a year
일년이나 갇혀 지냈던 놈인데
하룻밤 새에 재판을 열더니
and overnight they decide
to hold a trial
사형집행을 발표해요?
and pronounce a death sentence?
뭘 기대했나?
What did you expect?
하산은 라마디 시장에서
일반인 129명을 날려버린 놈일세
Hasan blew up 129 civilians
in the marketplace in Ramadi.
그건 저도 알아요
I know what he did.
미국 본토에 임박한
테러에 대한 정보를
I also know he's got intel
가지고 있다는 것도 알죠
about an imminent attack
on U.S. soil.
지난 3개월 동안이나
입다물던 놈이잖나
He's been dangling
this so-called attack
for the last three months.
Yeah.
집행을 막아주면
우리한테 불지도 모르죠
And now he'll come clean
if we commute his sentence.
더는 이라크 법에 관여할 수 없어
We don't dictate law
to the Iraqis anymore.
그들의 사법권이야
This is their jurisdiction.
하산은 그들의 죄수고
And Hasan is their prisoner.
데이빗
David...
잠시만요
Hold on a second.
He's Abu Nazir's
bomb maker, David.
놈은 알부 나지르의
폭탄 전문가였어요
놈의 사형집행이 끝나면
정보는 영원히 사라져요
Execute him now, and everything
he knows is gone forever.
거기서 멈추게 다 끝난 일이야
It's over.
감옥으로 향하는 길이예요
JSOC에 탄원서라도 넣어줘요
I'm on my way to the prison now.
At least petition JSOC.
- 이라크군에 항소하도록
- JSOC도 이 이상은 무리야
- Have them appeal to the Iraqi Army.
- JSOC can't do anything either.
CIA 부서장이잖아요
가능하다는 거 알아요
David, you're a CIA deputy
director... you can do this.
- 끝난 일이라고 말했네
- 이대로는 못 끝내요
- I told you it's over.
- Please don't shut me down.
펠드먼 상원의원께서
찾고 계십니다
David, Senator Feldman's
looking for you.
- 금방 가겠다고 말씀드려
- 데이빗 제발요
- Tell him I'll be right there.
- David, please,
지금이 마지막 기회예요
this is
my last chance with Hasan.
- 캐리 그만 가야겠네
- 데이빗
- Carrie, I have to go.
- David...
전화 끊겠네
I'm hanging up.
Estes didn't go for it.
에스테스가 도와주지 않았어
I knew he wouldn't.
예상했던 일이지만
Is that him?
- 녀석이야?
- 네
Yes.
I'm not sure we can trust him.
믿을 수 있는지 확신할 순 없어요
Can he get me inside or not?
날 들여보내 줄 수 있대?
가능하댔어요
He says he can.
2분 밖에 못드려요
Now you have only two minutes.
이해하셨죠? 2분이예요
Understand what I say...
two minutes.
이브라힘
Ibrahim...
I tried to get the
Agency to intervene,
기관에 도움을 요청했지만
거절당했어
but they couldn't do anything.
미안해
I'm sorry.
그렇다면 할 말 없소
So I have nothing to say to you.
가족들이 숨어 있다고 했잖아
Ibrahim, you said
your family was in hiding,
목숨의 위협을 받는다고
afraid for their lives.
그들을 아만으로 보내줄게
I can get them to Amman.
아는걸 말해주면
Tell me what you know,
그들의 안전을 보장할게
and I will personally
guarantee their safety.
당신 말을 어떻게 믿지?
Why should I believe
you will do what you say?
- 가야해요
- 2분이랬잖아
We have to go.
You said two minutes.
간수들이 오고 있어요
The guards, they are coming.
시간이 더 필요해
I need more time.
날 못믿는다고?
You don't believe me?
어쩌면 널 믿은게
실수일지도 모르지
Well, maybe I was wrong
to believe you.
스스로를 중요한 사람이라고 했잖아
알부 나지르의 테러 정보를 가지고 있다고
You said you were
an important man.
You said you had information
about an attack by Abu Nazir.
- 정보는 있소
- 증명해 봐
- I have information.
- Prove it.
그러지 않으면
Because unless you do,
가족들의 보호는 책임못져
I won't protect your family.
시간이 없어 제발!
Please, we're out of time!
내 가족들을
My family!
보호하겠다고 약속해!
You promised to protect them!
10개월 후
You're listening to "Jim
Dawkins in the Morning."
Wake up, Washington.
This is Dave sitting in
for Jim Dawkins.
We got a lot
on the topic today.
So why don't you get
your phones ready
and give us a call.
They say that Washingtonians
are apathetic and...
♪ ♪
어젯밤 23시에
Last night, at 2300 GMT,
지상 정보원 중에 한명이
one of our ground assets
produced a live lead
코렌갈 밸리에 적군 기지가
있다는 정보를 전했네
on an enemy operating base
in the Korengal Valley.
반갑군 캐리
Nice of you to join us, Carrie.
어떻게 부서에서
브리핑을 할 때마다
How is it you are
the only analyst
매번 지각하는 분석가가
자네뿐인지 궁금하군
in this section that can't
get to a briefing on time?
모두가 자리를 지켰으면 했네만
I wanted the whole
group to hear this.
1시간 이내에
델타팀이 도착해서
Within the hour,
Delta Team was on site.
우리 목록에 있던
다수의 반란군을 확인했지
where they identified multiple
insurgents on our hit list.
몇 분 뒤에
UH-60 블랙호크 2기가
Minutes later, two UH-60
Blackhawk gunships
8000발의 사격으로
지역을 강타했네
lit the target with
over 8,000 rounds.
13명의 적군을 사살했지
All 13 hostiles
were confirmed kills.
작전을 수행하던 중에
But, during the sweep,
델타팀 중 한명이
뭔가를 발견했네
one of the deltas found
something else...
자물쇠가 걸린 방이었어
a padlocked door
to an interior room.
여기부턴 직접 영상을
확인해보길 바라네
I wanted you
to see for yourselves.
- 당장 엎드려!
- 일으켜 세워
Get the fuck down!
Get him on his feet!
뭐라고 하셨죠?
What did you say?
난 미국인이요
I'm an American.
우리군으로 밝혀졌네
Turns out he's one of ours.
해병대 상사 니콜라스 브로디
Marine Sergeant Nicholas Brody.
2003년 초에 전사로 기록됐고
MIA since early 2003
and presumed dead...
지금까지는 당연히
죽은줄 알았지
until now.
파트너는 어떻게 됐죠?
What happened to his partner?
브로디는 정찰대 저격수였고
둘이서 팀으로 움직일텐데요
Brody was a scout sniper.
They work in pairs.
토마스 워커 상등병도
같이 사라졌잖아요
Corporal Thomas Walker also
went missing that day.
브로디 상사에 따르면
According to Sergeant Brody,
워커는 억류 중에
사망했다고 하네
Walker was killed
during their captivity.
그렇다고 해서
여러분들의 공로가
But that shouldn't dampen
훼손당할 일은 없을거야
what is a major win
for the agency and for everyone
자네들은 스스로에게
박수를 보내도 좋아
in this room.
You should all take a moment...
give yourselves a big hand.
자네들 덕분에
미국의 영웅이 귀환했으니
Because of you, an American hero
is coming home.
잘했네
Good job.
What were his exact
words, please?
정확히 뭐라고 하던가?
미국의 전쟁포로가
변절했다고 했어요
An American prisoner of war
has been turned.
영어로 말하던가?
He said this in English?
네 경비원들에게
끌려나가기 직전에
Yes. He whispered it
into my ear
제 귀에다 속삭였어요
right before the
guards pulled me away.
변절이라는 말은
And when he used
the expression "turned..."
알부 나지르를 위해
일한다는 뜻이죠
He meant turned...
working for Abu Nazir.
왜 지금에서야 이 말을 하는건가?
Why am I just hearing
about this now?
10분전만 하더라도
Because until ten minutes ago,
이라크나 아프간에 전쟁포로가
있는 줄도 몰랐으니까요
I didn't know there were any P.O.W.'s
still alive in Iraq or Afghanistan.
그러니까 알부 나지르가...
So you're suggesting
that Abu Nazir...
자네는 알부 나지르가
You're suggesting
that Abu Nazir
안전가옥에 요원을 심어서
planted intelligence in
his own safe house
우리가 브로디를 구출하도록
유도했단 말인가?
just so we could recover
Sergeant Brody?
미친 소리처럼 들리는 건 알아요
I realize it sounds
like a reach.
그 말 그대로네
To say the least.
검문소 근처에 놈을 떨궈놓고
Why not just drop him
near a checkpoint
스스로 도망친 것처럼
보이게 할 수도 있었잖아
and make it look
like he escaped.
굳이 13명의 동료를
희생할 필요없이
Why would you sacrifice
13 trained fighters?
알부 나지르는
철두철미 하니까요
Because Abu Nazir
is playing the long game.
이러면 아무도 의심하지 않겠죠
This way, no one
suspects a thing.
- 자네를 제외하고?
- 네 그래요
Except you.
Yeah, except me.
그래
Yeah.
내일 아침이면 브로디가
독일에서 돌아와요
And Sergeant Brody's due home
from Germany tomorrow morning,
22시간도 안남았어요
which gives us
just under 22 hours.
뭘 어쩌려고?
To do what?
To authorize a
surveillance package.
감시 허가를 받아야죠
핸드폰을 추적하고
집에 도청장치도 설치하고
To tap his phones,
wire his house,
놈이 가는 장소를 미행하고요
follow him wherever he goes.
데이빗이 절대로
허가 안해줄텐데
David will never sign off
on that and you know it.
물론 그렇겠죠
Of course he won't.
백악관에선 홍보용
용사가 필요할테고
The White House needs
a poster boy for the war,
데이빗은 그를 이용하려 하겠죠
and David just served
him up on a platter.
당신을 찾은 이유가 그거예요
That's why I'm coming to you.
직감만으로 정하기엔
너무 어려운 문제일세
I'm not going over his
head, not on a hunch.
제가 옳다면요?
놈이 테러범이라면?
But if I'm right,
if he is a terrorist,
놈이 비행기에서
내리는 순간부터
we need eyes and ears
on Brody from the minute
- 철저하게 감시해야죠
- 그럴일 없네
he steps off the plane.
- Never happen.
- But...
- 하지만
- 그건 불가능해 캐리
Out of the question.
Carrie...
좋아요 그럼 어떻게 하죠?
All right, fine.
What do I have to do?
안전가옥에서 누출된 정보가
의도된 거라는 걸 증명해
Prove that the safe house
leak was planted.
적어도 진실성을 의심할
증거라도 내어놓던가
Or at least give me a reason
to doubt its authenticity.
전 패널티 박스에 있어요 사울
I'm in the penalty box, Saul.
접선책하고도 5000마일이나
떨어져 있다고요
I'm 5,000 miles away
from my contacts.
책상 뒤에서 요원들
모집하는건 불가능해요
I can't collect intelligence
from behind a desk.
Find a way.
방법을 찾아봐
그런 눈으로 보지 말고
No, don't look at me that way.
우리는 같은 적과 싸우려고
여기 있는거잖나
We're all fighting
the same enemy here.
We're ready for you,
Sergeant Brody.
준비가 끝났습니다 브로디 상사
당신 브리핑이요
Your debriefing.
I want to call my wife first.
아내에게 먼저 전화하고 싶소
Oh, I think that's mine.
- 내 전화인가 봐
- 아니
Oh, no. Oh...
그냥 받지마
Don't get it. Don't.
아이들일지도 몰라
It might be one of my kids.
여보세요
Hello.
제시카?
Jessica?
나야 브로디
It's me. Brody.
브로디?
Brody?
제스 부탁이야 얘기 좀 해
Come on, Jess, talk to me.
무슨 말을 하길 바래?
What do you want me to say?
당신 괜찮다고 말해줘
Tell me that you're okay.
괜찮지 않아
I'm not okay.
괜찮은 거랑은 아주 거리가 멀어
I'm a long way from okay.
Hey.
Mom!
- 엄마
- 너희 누나는?
Where's your sister?
조디랑 영화보러
가신줄 알았는데요
I thought you were
at the movies with Jody.
대나 방에 있니?
Dana!
Is she in her room?
엄마 / 나랑 가자
Mom...
Come with me. Dana?!
대나 / 잠깐만요
Mom, just wait a second.
너희들에게 알려줄 소식이 있어
Come on. I have some
incredible news for you guys.
엄마 제발요
Mom! Come on, Mom!
대나! / 들어가시면 안되요
Dana!
Mom, don't go in there!
엄마 저도 막으려고 했어요
Mom, just...
Tried to stop her.
예정보다 일찍 왔네?
How come you're home so early?
저건 누구니? / 젠더야 / 젠더?
Who is he?
Xander.
Xander...
당장 여길 나가라
you need to leave right now.
나중에 문자할게
I'll text you later.
자켓 챙겨야지
Xan, your jacket.
왜 그렇게 소란 피워?
Why are you making such
a big deal out of this, Mom?
그게 네 거짓말 때문인지
아님 마약 때문인지 했갈리네
Gee, Dana, I don't know, it's
either the lying or the drugs.
동생을 돌봤어야 하는거 아니니?
You're supposed to be looking
after your brother.
얘가 집에 불이라도 지른대?
Well, he didn't
burn down the house.
내가 시키는대로 하면
어디가 덧나니?
Why don't you just do what
you say you're gonna do
엄마 / 왜?
for a change? What?
Mom!
중요하게 할말이 있다면서요
You said you had something
important to tell us.
젠장!
Shit!
무슨 일인데?
What, Ma?
둘다 이리 오거라
Come here, you two.
Touchdown in about two hours.
2시간이면 도착할 겁니다
필요하신 거라도?
You need anything?
아뇨 괜찮아요
No, I'm good. Thanks.
우선 가족들과
시간을 보내신 후에
You'll have some time
with your family first.
부통령님을 만나게 될겁니다
Then you'll meet
the Vice President,
그 분이 주요 언론에
당신을 소개할거고요
who'll introduce you to
every major media outlet
in the whole country.
앤드류 공군기지에
많은 인파가 모이고 있습니다
The turnout is overwhelming
here at Andrews Air Force Base
니콜라스 브로디 상사가
도착하기로 한 시간이
where Sergeant Nicholas Brody
is scheduled to land
2시간이 남지 않은 가운데
in just under two hours.
백악관 대변인의 발표에 따르면
Now a White House spokesman
confirms
부통령의 참석도
예정되었다고 합니다
that the Vice President
will be on hand.
아빠에 대해 기억나는건 있어?
Do you even remember him?
별로
Not really.
알려진 바에 따르면
니콜라스 브로디 상사는
As we reported, Sergeant Brody
is one of two Marines
8년 전에 전사한 것으로
알려진 2명 가운데 하나로
who went missing in action
eight years ago,
during a mission into
Iraq, near the Syrian border.
A former Marine Scout sniper,
Sergeant Brody was operating
in hostile territory
when his spotter...
안녕 브로디
Hi, Brody.
The soldiers
were then separated...
갈거야? 말거야?
You coming or not, Mom?
우리가 늦는 것도 웃기잖아
'Cause I don't think it'd
appropriate if we were late.
그래 코트 가져다 줄래?
Yeah, let me just get my coat.
정말로 그 드레스 입게?
Are you really wearing
that dress?
But after the announcement
that Sergeant Brody,
in fact, survived
the eight-year ordeal and was
greeted by a wave of enthusiasm
from an American public
eager to greet a true hero.
More details on
Sergeant Brody's captivity
are expected to come out
over the coming days,
but a military spokesman...
엄마 오늘 예쁘네요
You look pretty, Mom.
고맙구나
Thank you.
시작하자
Let's go.
거실부터 시작해
Start in the living room.
30분 남았어요
I got 30 minutes.
다시 보니 반갑구나 캐리
And good to see
you, too, Carrie.
저건 누구예요?
Who the fuck is he?!
진정해 내 동생 맥스다
Relax, it's all good.
It's my brother Max.
맥스 고객님께 인사해야지
Max, say hi to the client.
안녕하세요
Hi.
닉이랑 에디는 어쩌고요?
What happened
to Nick and Eddie?
예산이 빡빡해서 말이다
Out of your price range.
하루에 천달러라고 말했잖니
네가 준 돈으론 이게 전부다
I told you, for a grand a day,
it's gonna be bare bones.
마음에 안드냐?
Hey, you got
a bad feeling about this?
그만두고 싶으시다면
You want to roll this thing up
시작하기 전에 미리 말하거라
before we get started,
you just say the word.
도청기와 카메라는
방마다 설치해요
Eyes and ears in every room.
그리고 저희 집에다가
모니터 세팅해주시고요
Then it's back to my place
to set up the monitors.
축하행사 늦출 방법은 없나?
No way you could delay
the ceremony?
그랬다간 완전히
바보처럼 보일거야
Not without looking
like a complete asshole.
화장실에서 토하는 중이야
He's in the head now
puking his guts out.
군의관들의 검사 결과는
정상인 걸로 알았는데
I thought the Army docs
did a complete psych eval.
- 그래 맞아
- 그럼 뭐가 문제야?
They did.
So what's the problem?
나도 모르지 데이빗
8년간이나 구멍 속에서
I don't know, David.
Maybe eight years at the bottom
갖혀 살았던 거랑
관련이 있을지도
of a hole had something
to do with it.
전에도 말했지만
부통령께서 오실거야
I have the Vice President
arriving as we speak.
녀석은 웃으면서
영웅처럼 손을 흔들어야 해
And I need him smiling and
waving like a hero,
망할 추수감사절 축제
퍼레이드처럼 말이야
like it's the fucking
Macy's Day Parade.
대통령께서 감사인사
전하라고 하시더군
The President asked me
to thank you personally.
다음 국장 후보자 명단을
I have to think the short list
for the directorship
더 줄이게 될 것 같군
just got a lot shorter.
배려에 감사드립니다 각하
Well, I appreciate
the consideration, sir.
하지만 그걸 목적으로
한 일은 아닙니다
Not that I'm pushing for it.
자네야 그렇겠지
Sure you are.
Hi, Dad.
아빠 안녕
Dana.
대나
여행은 어땠어요?
How was your trip?
예쁘게 자랐구나
Look at how beautiful you are.
크리스
Chris.
만나서 반가워요
Pleased to meet you.
Hug him, Chris.
포옹을 해야지 크리스
어머니는?
Where's Mom?
언제 돌아가셨어?
When?
4년전에
Four years ago.
브로디 상사 부통령이 오셨어요
Sergeant Brody,
the Vice President's here.
브로디 상사
Sergeant Brody.
영광일세
It's an honor.
감사합니다 각하
Thank you, sir.
당신 괜찮아? / 그래
You okay?
Yeah.
좋은 아침일세 해병 제군들
Good morning, Marines.
좋은 아침입니다
Good morning, sir!
좋은 아침이라고 했네만
I said, "Good morning, Marines."
좋은 아침입니다
Good morning, sir!
쉬게나
Stand at ease.
브로디 상사
Sergeant Brody, on behalf
of the President
미합중국 대통령과
국가를 대신해
of the United States and
a grateful nation,
자네의 생환을 축하하네
it is my privilege to welcome
you home!
Oorah!
니콜라스 브로디 상사입니다
Sergeant Nicholas Brody.
감사합니다 부통령 각하
Thank you, Mr. Vice President.
저는 연설에
능숙한 편은 아닙니다
I'm not really too good
at making speeches.
가족들 가운데선
제 부인이 달변이죠
My wife does most of the talking
in the family.
비록 이름은 모르지만
Even though
I can't mention 'em by name,
저를 구출해 준
스페셜포스 대원들께 감사합니다
I want to thank the Special
Forces team that saved my life.
그리고 저를 위해 기도해주신
And thanks
to all of you out there
모든 분들께도 감사드립니다
for your prayers
and your good wishes.
그 기도가 제게
도움이 되었으니까요
It made all the difference.
그 무엇보다도
제가 감사하고 싶은건
Most of all,
I want to say...
바로 제 가족들입니다
I want to say
thank you to my family
저의 부재를 견뎌오며
저의 생환을 믿었기에
for their strength
in my absence...
지금 이 순간이
있다고 생각합니다
and for their undying faith
this day would come.
저는 행운아입니다
I'm a lucky man.
인간승리네
Guy's got game.
설치하는데 얼마나 걸리죠?
How long before you're set up?
브로디가 집에 도착하기 전까진
신호가 잡힐거야
The feed will be live
by the time
Sergeant Brody
gets back to his house.
More details on
Sergeant Brody's captivity
are expected to come out.
형이랑 캐리는
So, uh, you and Carrie,
얼마나 오래 알고 지낸거야?
how long you guys
known each other?
오래됐지
Long enough.
우리가 누굴 위해 일하는지
'Cause I'd kind of feel
a lot better
명확히 알 수 있다면
if I had a clear picture
기분이 나아질거 같아서
about who we're dealing with.
지금 연방법을 12개나
위반하는 중이잖아
We are breaking, like,
12 federal laws.
명확히 알고 싶다?
You would, would you?
A clearer picture?
그냥 입 닥치고
할 일이나 하지 그래
Why don't you shut the fuck up
and get back to work, okay?
야
Hey...
미안하다 말해줄 수 있는건
I'm sorry, um... let's just say
그녀가 절실하다는 것 뿐이야
that she's a little intense.
그래
Yeah.
그건 뭐야?
What's that?
저 여자가 아스피린 병 속에
It's what she hides
in her aspirin bottle
아스피린 대신 숨기던 거
instead of aspirin.
편두통이 오길래 찾아봤더니...
I have one of my migraines
coming on, so...
이리 줘봐
Let me see that.
What do you think it is?
뭐라고 생각해?
나도 모르지
I don't know.
내가 운전하지
I'm driving.
그게 좋은 생각일까?
Are you sure
that's a good idea?
그냥 아빠가 운전하게 해
Jesus, Mom, just let him drive.
그래 알았어
Okay, I guess.
해병씨!
Marine!
Mike?
마이크?
- 잘 돌아왔어
- 고마워
Welcome back.
Thanks, man.
괜찮나? 좋아보이는 걸
How you holding up?
You look good.
집에 오니까 좋을 수 밖에
It's great to be home.
자네가 돌아와서 나도 좋군
It's great to have you home.
진짜로 여기서 근무해?
This is for real?
You stayed in?
국군 정보부지
Military intelligence.
알아 많은 사람 중에
하필이면 나라는 거
I know, right?
Me, of all people, huh?
메간은 어떻게 지내?
And Megan? How's she?
깨진지 오래됐어
Long gone, buddy.
3번째 여행 직전에 이혼당했지
She divorced me between
my second and third tours.
Ah.
지금 이런말 하긴 뭐하지만
Look, I hate to bring this
up, but Langley wants to
랭글리에서 자네한테
후속보고를 받고 싶어해
schedule a follow-up to
your debrief in Germany.
- 약속 잡기를 원하던데
- 언제요?
- They asked me to arrange it.
- When?
- Tomorrow.
- Tomorrow?!
- 내일이요
- 내일요?
저도 똑같이 말했어요 하지만...
I know. I said the
same thing, but...
에스테스가
빠른 일처리를 원하거든
this guy Estes, he wants it
done sooner than later.
- 이제 막 도착한걸요
- 괜찮아 제스
He just got here.
It's okay, Jess.
빨리 끝내는 게 낫지
I'd rather just
get it over with.
아침에 차를 보낼게
Well, I'll send
a car in the morning.
좋아
Good.
보고가 끝나면
And when you're up for it...
'Greeks'에 가서 같이
맥주랑 스테이크 좀 썰자고
I'm taking you to the Greeks
for some steak and beer, buddy,
우리가 만회해야 할
시간이 넘치고 넘치니까
'cause we got a lot of lost
time to start making up for.
Huh?
다시 보니까 너무 반갑다
Yeah. God, it's good
to see you, buddy.
나도 그래
You, too.
Look.
저걸봐
우리가 유명해졌나봐
We're famous.
집에 도착하기 전까진
신호가 잡힐거라면서요
You said you'd be ready
by the time they got home.
사소한 결함이야
몇 분만 시간을 줘
It's just a minor glitch,
give me a few minutes.
페인트 새로 칠했네
You painted the house.
마이크의 동생이 해줬어요
Mike's brother did it.
동생이 도급업자야
저가에 해줬거든
He's a contractor.
He gave us a really great rate.
색상은 마음에 들어?
What do you think of the color?
마음에 들어
I like it.
Come on.
가자 내부도 보여줄게
I'll show you
what we did inside.
기분이 어떠신가요?
How's it feel to be back?
노란 리본 배경으로
가족사진 찍어도 될까요?
Can we get a group shot
with the yellow ribbon?
그렇게 할까?
What do you think?
- 그러자
- 그럴게요
Sure.
Come on, come on.
나무 앞에서 줄만 서주세요
Yeah. If you could just line up
in front of the tree, yeah.
가족사진이 근사할거예요
Family shot.
That's fantastic.
크게 웃어봐요
Big smile.
정보를 수집하기 힘들어요
I'm having trouble collecting
that intel. I need you to get me
내일 브로디의 브리핑에
저를 넣어주세요
into Sergeant Brody's debrief
tomorrow morning.
그래서 어쩔 생각인가?
And what good
would come of that?
전 훈련받은 심문관이니
몇가지 질문을 하겠죠
I'm a trained interrogator.
I'll ask him a few questions,
그리고 몇군데 찔러봐야죠
poke around his story a little.
데이빗이 분명히 말했네
관련자만 참가 가능하지
principals only.
데이빗은 절 징계할
생각 뿐인걸요
David's all about punishing me.
게다가 바그다드의 일을
모르고 있고요
And not just for what
happened in Baghdad.
- 그를 비난하는 건가?
- 아뇨 그런게 아니라
- Do you blame him?
- No, but...
개인 감정 때문이 아니에요
저도 자격이 있다고요
this shouldn't be personal;
I belong in that room.
얌전히 굴텐가?
Will you behave yourself?
캐리?
Carrie?
- 캐리?
- 미안해
Carrie?
Sorry.
듣고 있어요
Uh, yeah.
우선 약속부터 하게
I need you to promise.
소란피우지 않고
판을 깨지 않겠다고
You will raise
no eyebrows in there.
You will break no china.
약속할게요
I promise.
좋아
Good.
브로디 상사를 만나게 해주지
Then you can have your face
time with Sergeant Brody.
Thank you, Saul.
고마워요 사울
그래
Yep.
젠장할
Oh, Christ.
잘되요?
Well?
안녕하신가 친구
Hello, Big Brother.
내일은 언제 올까?
So when do you want
me back tomorrow?
캐리
Carrie.
9시 출근이니까
8시까지 오시면 되요
I need to be in the office
by 9:00, so get here at 8:00.
알았어
Okay.
여보세요?
Hello?
말씀하세요
누구 전화였어?
Who was that?
맙소사 놀랐잖아
Oh, Jesus, you scared me.
몰라 그냥 끊었어
Nobody. They hung up.
How was your shower?
샤워는 어땠어?
당신 정말 아름답군
God, you look beautiful.
와인 한잔 할래? 병을 땄는데
How about a glass of wine?
I opened a bottle.
무슨 속셈인지 알겠어
Oh, I see what this is now.
조명을 흐리게 하고
내게 술을 먹이다니
Dimming the lights,
plying me with liquor.
그거 확실한 거야?
Is it that obvious?
어느정도는
Kind of.
나이트가운 입은 모습이
마음에 드는걸
I gotta say, I like you in
that nightgown, though.
우리 엄마가 입던게
나이트가운이지
My mother wears a nightgown.
이건 네글리제야
This is a negligee.
와인은 어떻게 할래?
How about that wine,
what do you say?
좋지
Sure.
태그가 붙어 있었어
The tag is still...
Is that okay?
당신 괜찮아?
Yeah.
그래
제스
Jess...
제스 / 응?
Hmm?
세상에...
Oh, my...
Hey.
대체 무슨 일을...?
What they did to you...
Hey. Hey...
- 자긴
- 제스
Baby...
Oh, Jess...
Oh, God...
Hey.
미안해
I'm sorry.
괜찮아
No, it's okay.
정말 미안해
I'm so sorry.
여기 앉아봐
Let's sit down here.
다 끝났어
It's over.
모든게 끝난거야
It's over now, baby.
내가 집에 왔잖아
I'm home.
그래
Okay.
I'm home now, baby.
그래
Okay. Oh, baby.
Oh, God...
It hurts...
What time is it?
- 지금 몇시죠?
- 8시 15분
Quarter after 8:00.
브리핑에 늦겠어
The debrief!
I'm late!
- 젠장
- 도넛 먹을래?
- Shit!
- Want a donut?
전화가 두번 걸려왔어요
Two calls came in;
both hang-ups.
밤에 한번 아침에 한번
Yeah?
One last night, one this morning.
두번 모두 부인이 받았지만
아무런 대답없이 끊더군요
Both times the wife answered;
both times there was no one
on the other end of the line.
Did a number pop up on a tracer?
번호는 추적했어?
No, and the calls were blocked.
Is there any way that...
아뇨 통화가 바로 끊겨서
다른 방법이?
영장 없이는 불가능하지
No, not without a subpoena.
버질 누군가가 브로디랑
Look, Virgil,
if somebody's trying
연락을 시도중이예요
기회는 한번 뿐이라고요
to make contact with Brody,
it'll only happen once.
그렇게 된다면
우리가 잡아내겠지
And when it does,
we'll be there.
모든게 잘되고 있으니 진정해
All right?
It's all good. Relax.
좋아요 옷부터 입어야겠네요
All right.
I've got to get dressed.
이 방에 계신 분들이
Many of the men and women
in this room are involved
당신을 구출했던 작전에
직접 개입된 사람들이죠
in the operation which resulted
in your rescue, so we take
그러니 우리들은 당신을
특별히 환영합니다
an extra measure of pride
in welcoming you.
감사합니다
Thank you, sir.
독일에서의 브리핑 자료는
모두 읽어봤습니다
Now, we've all
read your debrief
from Germany, so
today we just have
오늘은 알카에다를
대적하는데 필요한
a few more questions...
clarifications, really...
몇가지 정보를 얻기위해
질문을 드릴겁니다
that might help us in our
ongoing fight against Al Qaeda.
- I understand.
- Good.
- 알겠습니다
- 좋아요
Good. We'll, uh, start
with Stuart Strickland,
이라크 세션의 수석 분석관인
스튜어트 스트릭랜드부터
시작하지
lead analyst in
our Iraq section.
브로디 상사님
만나서 영광입니다
Sergeant Brody,
it's a pleasure.
억류당하시고 나서 몇주동안
A few weeks after your capture,
Special Forces conducted
스페셜포스가 가르마에 있는
a direct action mission against
예전 경찰 본부에서
작전을 실시했는데요
a former police HQ in Garma...
브리핑 자료에 따르면
According to your debrief,
감금 생활의 대부분을
most of your incarceration
다마스커스 외곽지역의
군사시설에서 보내셨는데
was spent at a secret military
facility outside Damascus.
랜드마크라던가
구조적인 세부사항을
What landmarks
알려주신다면 저희가
정확한 위치를 찾는데 도움이
or structural details can you
give us to help pinpoint...?
8개월전 아프간에 위치한
적들의 작전 기지로
Eight months you were
smuggled overland
육로를 통해
몰래 이송이 되었는데요
to an enemy operating base in
Afghanistan.
그렇게 오랜 시간이 지났는데도
Now, after so many years,
what prompted...?
브로디 상사님
전 캐리 매티슨입니다
Sergeant Brody, my name
is Carrie Mathison.
이라크에서는
작전 지원팀으로 근무했었죠
I served as a case officer
in Iraq.
당신 사진을 전사자 명단에서
Your picture was on
our MIA wall.
5년간 매일 봤었죠
I saw it every day
for five years.
살아서 뵙게 되다니 반갑군요
It's good to meet you in person.
감사합니다
Thank you, ma'am.
일찍 구하지 못한걸
죄송하게 생각합니다
I'm sorry we were unable
to find you sooner.
걱정해주셔서 감사합니다
I appreciate that.
I'd like to start
괜찮으시면 감금 초기의
몇일에 대해 여쭤볼게요
with the first few days
of your captivity
if you don't mind.
Not at all.
- 괜찮아요
- 심문이 시작된 건 언제였죠?
How soon after you were taken
did the interrogations begin?
Pretty much right away.
거의 바로였죠
What did they want to know?
어떤 정보를 원하던가요?
Anything I could tell 'em
about U.S. ground operations,
지상 작전에 대한
모든 정보를 원했죠
보급루트 통신코드
교전수칙 등등
supply routes, communication
codes, rules of engagement.
독일에서의 브리핑에 따르면
When you were debriefed
in Germany,
정보를 전혀 불지 않으셨더군요
you said you gave up
no such information.
SERE 훈련을 잘 받았으니까요
My SERE training was excellent.
And Corporal Walker?
워커 상등병도 그런가요?
Ma'am?
네?
Did he give anything up?
그가 정보를 팔았을까요?
We were never interrogated
together, so I don't know.
심문은 각각 행해져서
거기까진 모르겠군요
But still you must have
wondered, especially
그래도 의문점은
가지고 계실텐데요
특히 그의 죽음을
알게 된 이후에는 말이죠
after you learned of his death.
질문의 요점이 있는건가?
I'm assuming
there's a point
to all this, Carrie?
물론이죠 아시겠지만
There is, sir.
As you know, the first 72 hours
군인이 포로로 잡히면
처음 72시간이 가장 힘들죠
after a soldier's capture
are critical.
What he knows can be
used by the enemy
포로가 알고 있는 정보가
그 시간을 넘기면
가치가 상당히 떨어지니까요
during that period to
devastating effect.
요점은 브로디 상사에게
정보를 빼내려는 행위를
The point is Sergeant Brody
stopped being a source
꽤나 빠르게 포기한데다가
of actionable intelligence
fairly quickly,
8년이나 살려줬다는 거예요
and yet he was kept
alive for eight more years.
그 이유를 묻고 싶군요
I'd like to ask him
if he knows why.
제 스스로도 놀라는 일이죠
I often wondered that myself.
Who was your interrogator?
심문자가 누구였죠?
An Al Qaeda commander.
알카에다 지휘관 자야디였어요
His name was Zayadi.
Zayadi?
자야디요?
스스로 알려준 이름은 그랬어요
That's what he told me
his name was, anyway.
Was this him?
이 사람인가요?
No.
아뇨
But you know who this man is.
누구인지는 아시겠죠?
Of course.
물론이죠
Every Marine in country
was briefed
모든 해병들이 알고 있죠
on high-value targets.
최우선 목표로
브리핑 받으니까요
- 만난 적은 있나요?
- 알부 나지르요?
Did you ever meet him?
Abu Nazir?
심문이 진행될 때
모습을 나타낸 적이 있나요?
Was he ever present during
any of your interrogations?
아뇨
No.
Look again.
한번 보세요
Sergeant Brody?
브로디 상사님?
No, I never met him.
아뇨 만난 적 없습니다
What-what... what about Walker?
워커 상등병은요?
알부 나지르에 대해
언급한 적이 있나요?
Did he ever mention Abu Nazir?
아뇨
No.
You sure?
Carrie, how many times
- 확실한가요?
- 캐리
얼마나 같은 대답을
들어야 만족하겠나?
does the man have
to answer the question?
It's just, I'm just
a little surprised, sir.
조금 신기해서 그래요
Abu Nazir was in charge
of coordinating attacks
당시 연합군에 대한
공격을 지휘한 건
against coalition forces
at the time.
다름아닌 나지르였잖아요
No one had more
2명의 미국인 포로가
수중에 들어왔는데
reason to sit down with the only
two American P.O.W.'s
만나길 바라지 않았을까요?
in his custody.
Well, apparently, he didn't.
듣자하니 그랬나보군
Is there anything else, Carrie?
다른 질문이 있나? 캐리?
No, sir, that's it.
아뇨 없습니다
감사합니다 브로디 상사님
Thank you, Sergeant Brody.
고맙소
Thank you.
계속하죠 상사
Moving on, Sergeant Brody,
당신이 포로로 있을 때
보거나 들었던 것 중에
I'd like to turn your attention
to anything you may have
witnessed
생각나는게 있는지 묻고 싶군요
or overheard when in captivity.
Remember Mrs. Base?
The math teacher?
Yeah.
- 베이스 선생님 기억해?
- 수학 선생 말야?
Yeah, she was, like, my
least-favorite teacher of all time.
She's so annoying.
내가 본 최고의 선생님이셨는데
Hey, can you guys
come in here a second?
- 완전 짜증이던데
- 너희들 잠깐 이리로 올래?
- 오늘밤 준비를 도와라
- 오늘밤 뭐 하는데요?
Hey, I need help
getting ready for tonight.
What's tonight?
아빠 부대의 친구들을
바베큐 파티에 초대했다
Some of your father's buddies
from Bravo Company are coming
over for a barbecue.
포대에서 옥수수 꺼내서
껍질 벗기고
There's a bag of corn
that needs to be shucked,
석쇠를 깨끗히 닦아놔라
and the grill needs
to be cleaned.
옥수수는 제가 할게요
I'll do the corn.
나도 여기 있어야해?
So, do I have to be here?
Why is everything always
a problem with you?
항상 뭐가 그리 불만이니?
I was just asking a question.
그냥 물어본거잖아
우리 사이에
문제가 있는건 알지만
I know things haven't
been easy between you and me.
지금 당장은 힘을 합쳐야 할때야
But we all have to find a way
to be there
for each other now, okay?
알았니? / 알았어
Yeah, okay.
Clean the grill.
석쇠 닦아라
Hello?
- 여보세요?
- 제스 나야
Hey, Jess.
어떻게 됐어?
Hey. How did it go?
아직도 랭글리야
I'm actually still here
at Langley.
브리핑룸에 갖혀있거든
I'm stuck in this debrief,
예상보다 길어질 거 같아
and it's taking a little
longer than I expected.
얼마나?
How much longer?
아마도 한 두시간 정도?
Oh, only an hour or two maybe.
5시에 다들 모이는거 잊지마
Well, don't forget,
everybody's coming at 5:00.
안늦을게
Sure. I won't be late.
잘있어 여보
Okay. Bye, honey.
Sergeant Brody
you're a man who's endured
a terrible ordeal.
Thank you, Mr. Vice President.
Anything?
뭔가 건졌어요?
As a matter of fact, yeah.
Brody just lied to his wife.
사실은 브로디가
부인에게 거짓말을 했어
- 말해보세요
- 차에 타고 있다는데
- Tell me.
- Max is tailing his town car.
브로디는 아직
랭글리에 있다고 했대
Brody just said
he was still at Langley,
운전사에겐 블루몬트
공원으로 가라고 했어
but he told his driver to
drop him off at Bluemont Park.
드디어 접촉을 시도하는군요
This is it.
He's making contact.
알았어요 거기서 뵈요
All right, I'll meet you there.
블루몬트 공원이 어디죠?
Where's-Where's Bluemont Park?
사울?
Saul?
안녕한가
대학 미팅에 늦어서 말야
Hey. Late for a
meeting off campus.
시험지가 깔고
앉을만큼 넘치거든
How many boards
can one man sit on?
캐리를 브리핑에
참가시킨게 자네란거 알아
You kissed Carrie Mathison
into my debrief this morning.
그녀의 요청이었나?
아님 자네 생각이었나?
I'm curious if that was
her request or yours.
노골적으로 부탁하던데
오히려 내가 놀란건
Hers. Frankly, I'm surprised
you didn't assign her yourself,
이라크에 있었던 유일한
요원을 자네가 제외한거지
since she's the only one in the
section who's ever been to Iraq.
이력이 문제가 아냐
내가 문제삼는건
It's not her resume
I have a problem with.
It's her temperament.
- 그녀의 기질이지
- 무슨 일 있었나?
What happened?
통상적인 후속조치를
아예 심문으로 만들더군
She turned a routine follow-up
into a cross-examination.
브로디를 알부 나지르랑
연결시키려고 하던걸
Kept trying to connect
Brody to Abu Nazir.
- 항상 나지르 타령이지
- 부정은 안하겠네
It's always Nazir with her.
I won't deny
she can be a little obsessive
on the subject.
강박관념이 있긴 하지
Is there something
I should know, Saul?
- 내가 모르는 게 있나?
- 나도 아는 건 없네만
Not that I'm aware of.
Because the last time
최근에 관련된 사건에선
그녀가 뇌물을 주고
I heard her like this,
she bribed her way
이라크 감옥에 침입해서
국제분쟁을 만들었거든
into an Iraqi prison,
caused an international crisis.
관심 가져줘서 고맙네
I appreciate your concern.
캐리도 교훈을 얻었겠지
Carrie has learned her lesson.
그리고 그녀의 우수성은
우리 둘다 알고 있잖나
And we both know
how good she is.
그녀에게 기회를 다시 주기로 했을 때
자네에게 했던 말 기억하나?
What did I tell you
when I agreed
to give her one more chance?
내가 애보기를 동의하는
조건이라고 했었지
You said only if I agreed
to do the babysitting.
안좋게 끝날거라고 했어
I said it would end badly.
자네 둘다 말야
For both of you.
그녀가 관련된 일이라면
자넨 냉정을 잃으니까
You've got a big blind spot
where she's concerned.
내 말을 믿게 나도 경험했어
Trust me.
I did, too.
결국 마누라는
팜 비치에 살고있고
Now my wife lives in Palm Beach,
자식들은 일년에
두 번 만나는 정도야
and I only see my kids
twice a year.
- 오디오는 고쳐졌어요?
- 곧 알게 되겠지
Did you fix the audio? Well, we'll know soon enough.
밴드셀 근처에
지향성 마이크를 설치했어
I set up a directional mic near the band shell. Max, switch
맥스 3번 채널로 돌려
to channel three.
1시 방향에서 누군가가
브로디에게 접근 중이예요
적색 코트입은 여성
Somebody's approaching Brody from 1:00... a female, dark red coat.
당신이 성공할 줄은
생각도 못했네요
I didn't think you'd be able to make it.
I don't understand why you had to go through Mike.
왜 마이크를 통해서
연락을 주신거죠?
직접 전화하지 그러셨어요
Why didn't you just call me yourself?
했어요 두번이나
I did. Twice. Are you recording this?
- 기록중이죠?
- 하지만 부인께서 받더군요
But your wife answered.
아무런 말도 못들었는데요
She didn't give me any messages.
Because I hung up.
제가 끊었으니까요
절 싫어해요 브로디
She hates me, Brody.
Hates you? Why?
- 싫어하다니요? 왜요?
- 제가 재혼했으니까요
Because I got remarried.
제시카는 그 사실을
모욕으로 받아들였죠
Jessica reacted like it was a personal insult.
Like I was publicly giving up hope that you
당신과 탐이 살아있다는
희망을 포기한거라고
and Tom were still alive.
What the...? Who the hell is she?
- 대체 저건 누구야?
- 헬렌 워커요 실종된 다른 해병의 부인이죠
Helen Walker. It's the wife of the other missing Marine.
적어도 브로디의
접선책은 아닌거네
Ah, well, then, she's not Brody's contact.
그냥 듣기나 하죠
Just keep listening.
펜타곤에선 둘다
죽었다고 했어요
The Pentagon said you both were dead.
And now they're refusing to give me any information
about what happened to Tom.
그리고 지금은 탐에게 생겼던 일을
아무것도 알려주지 않더군요
알고싶으신 게 뭡니까?
What do you want to know?
그이는 어떻게 죽었죠?
How he died. He's gone.
이미 죽은 사람이예요
어떻게가 중요한가요?
Does it really matter how it happened?
저한텐 중요해요
It does to me.
He was beaten to death.
죽을때까지 폭행당했죠
Were you there?
그 자리에 있었나요?
No.
아뇨
알려줘서 고마워요
Thank you for telling me.
집에 가야겠네요
바베큐 파티 시간에 맞춰야하니
I'm going home.
Want to be there in time for this barbecue.
Hold on a second.
잠깐만 기다려
Max, will you give us a minute?
맥스 잠깐 시간 좀 줄래?
맥스 벤에서 내려 달라고
Max, step out of the van.
I didn't think that this was any of my business.
Now I'm thinking that it is.
내가 상관할 일이
아니라고 생각했지만
이제는 상관해야겠어
클로자핀?
Clozapine?
죄송한데요
I'm sorry.
미리 말했어야 했나요?
Was I supposed to say something?
Just tell me I'm not out here
미친 사람을 돕기위해
감옥에 갈 위험을 감수하고
이러고 있는게 아니라고 말해봐
ritsking federal prison on behalf of a crazy person.
I am crazy. It's not funny.
- 전 미쳤는걸요
- 재미없어
정보부의 누군가가
이걸 찾았다고 생각해 봐
If anybody at the Agency finds out about this...
I've got a mood disorder, okay?
I looked it up, Carrie.
기분장애래요 됐나요?
이미 알아봤어 캐리
클로자핀은 항정신병제잖아
Clozapine's an anti-psychotic.
I'm dealing with it.
I've-I've been dealing with it since I was 22.
알아서 하고 있어요
22살 이후로 알아서 해왔고요
- 사울도 알아?
- 아뇨
- Does Saul know? - God, no.
No. Nobody does.
Don't act so shocked.
아무도 몰라요
충격받은 것처럼 행동하지 마요
그렇게 의외도 아니잖아요
I mean, it can't come as a complete surprise.
캐리 널 사랑하지만
솔직하게 말해야겠다
You know I love you, Carrie, but I got to be honest.
- 지금 하는 일들이 마음에 들지 않는구나
- 무슨 말씀이세요? 모든게 제 망상이라고요?
None of this is making me feel any better.
What are you saying?
That I'm making this shit up?
그럴지도 모르죠
제 머릿속 환상일지도
Well, maybe I am; you know, maybe it is all in my head,
but you're in it now, Virgil, up to your fucking neck,
하지만 당신도 깊게
연루됐잖아요 버질
당신의 괴짜 동생도 마찮가지고요
그러니까 배신은 꿈도 꾸지 마세요
and so is your weird little brother,
so don't even think about bailing on me.
You think for one minute you get away with this?
잠시만이라도 이걸
생각안할 수 없냐?
증거를 찾을 생각에...
I thought that once I had some proof...
뭔가 찾았니?
Do you have any?
뭐라도?
Anything?
브로디 상사를 의심할
심증이라도?
Even suggesting that Sergeant Brody's what you think he is?
- 없어요
- 그럼 변호사에게 연락해라
No.
Then get a lawyer.
내일 IG에 보고할 때
대동해야 할테니까
'Cause you're gonna need one when you report
to the IG first thing in the morning.
- Saul, please... - There isn't anything to say.
- 사울 제발요
- 더 할말은 없다
다시 테러가 발생하지
않을 확신이 필요했어요
I-I'm just making sure we don't get hit again.
Well, I'm glad someone's looking out for the country, Carrie.
그렇게까지 국가를 위하다니
기쁘구나 캐리
진심이예요 전에는 실수했지만
I'm serious... I missed something once before;
I won't... I can't let that happen again.
다시 그런 일이
발생되도록 할 수 없어요
벌써 10년이나 지났다
그 당시에는 모두가 실수했었지
It was ten years ago.
Everyone missed something that day.
- 모두가 그래도 전 안되요
- 난 이해한다
Yeah, everyone's not me. I understand that.
I doubt a grand jury will.
배심원도 이해해줄지
장담은 못하겠다만
제발요 당신이
저를 훈련시켰잖아요
Come on, you recruited me, Saul.
저를 교육시키고
현장에 내보냈잖아요
You trained me.
You put me in the field.
Tell me what I can do to make this right between us.
이걸 바로 잡으려면
뭘 해야할지 말해주세요
이건 대체 무슨 짓이냐?
What the fuck are you doing?
Good-bye, Carrie.
잘 있어라 캐리
망할! 젠장
Aw, fuck!
Shit. Shit.
You know, I'm shaking his hand...
너희들도 알겠지만
내가 악수했던 사람이
바로 부통령이었잖아
he's the vice president... and I suddenly realize...
그러다 이런 생각이 든거야
이 자식 이름도 모르고 있잖아
I don't even know the guy's name.
안녕
Geez, you don't call, you don't write...
전화도 없고 문자도 없고
We have to talk. 'Cause you can't keep ducking me.
우리 얘기 좀 해야해
계속 날 피하고 있잖아
피하는거 아니야
I'm not ducking you.
상황에 적응하려고 노력중이야
I'm just trying to deal with the situation. Yeah, well,
그건 당신만이 아니지
you're not the only one.
Look...
생각해 봐
I understand you want to do the right thing
옳은 일을 하려는 건
이해하고 지지해
and I support you, but, Jess...
하지만 제스
three days ago we were about to tell your kids.
3일 전만 하더라도
당신 아이들한테
We were talking about moving in together.
우리가 같이 살거라고
말하려던 중이었잖아
마이크 제발
Mike, please.
Hey, you want me to forget it?
그걸 잊고 싶은거야?
You know, all you got to do is tell me that it wasn't great between us.
우리 둘 사이에
아무일도 없었다고 말해봐
그는 내 남편이야 마이크
He's my husband, Mike.
타겠어요
They're gonna burn.
The burgers. Oh.
햄버거요
그래 여다
Right.
Here.
마이크가 엄마를 많이 도왔다며?
So, Mike's been a big help to your mom, huh?
He comes around whenever she needs him.
엄마가 필요할 때마다
도우러 와줬어요
You like him? Yeah, he's cool.
그를 좋아하니?
네 멋지잖아요
There you go.
이거 받아라 이건 엄마꺼다
One's for Mom. Thanks.
I'm just saying that I think
이런 생각이 들기 시작하네요
어디에 누군가가 저 남자를 보면서
that somebody somewhere is looking at him right now and thinking
의원이나 상원의원이
되지 않을까하는
congressman or senator or...
안그런가요?
You know?
사적인 질문 하나 할까요?
Can I ask you a personal question?
Don't you want to get a couple more drinks in me first?
먼저 날 취하게 하려는게
목적 아니었나요?
- 결혼 했어요?
- 아뇨
You're married? No.
But you wear a ring.
반지를 끼고 계신데
Oh, weeds out the guys looking for a relationship.
섹스하려고 접근하는
남자들을 제거하려고요
왜요?
What?
그냥 모르겠어요 그렇게 직설적으로
말하는 분은 처음이라
I... I don't know, I guess I've never
heard it put so bluntly before.
I just find it a lot easier not to screw things up with people I don't know.
알지도 못하는 사람들의 기분을 잡치는
것보다는 이게 훨씬 쉬웠거든요
모든게 그렇게
나쁜것 만은 아니에요
Come on, you can't be all that bad.
세상에서 유일하게
진실한 친구를 제가 배신했다면요?
What if I told you I betrayed
my only true friend in the world today,
그를 바보로 만들고
just played him for a fool,
35년의 경력을 위태롭게 하고
put his 35-year career at risk?
I would say that in this town you're in good company.
그래도 좋은 회사에서
일하신다고 말해드리죠
그건 그래요
Yeah.
한잔 더요
Another, please.
연주를 잘하네요
테이블로 옮길까요?
These guys are pretty good. You want to grab a table?
그냥 여기서 나가죠
I'd rather just get out of here.
Okay. Where should we go?
좋아요 어디로 갈까요?
I'm done making the decisions.
제가 결정 하나를 내렸으니
You're in charge now. Wow.
이젠 당신 차례예요
좋아요 마음에 드네요
Okay, I like it.
Are you coming? Hey, Carrie, are you okay?
가실까요? 캐리 괜찮아요?
What am I looking at here? His right hand.
- 뭘 보여주려고?
- 오른손을 보세요
- 초초한가 보네
- 아뇨 다시 보세요
He's just nervous.
No. No. Look again.
It's a pattern that repeats, like a musical phrase.
패턴이 반복되고 있어요
음악의 절처럼
There.
저기요
- 확신하긴 힘들군
- 아니요
That's hardly definitive. No.
기다려 보세요
Just... wait.
This is him outside his house.
이건 집 밖에서 찍은거고
이건 공군기지에서에요
And here he is at Andrews Air Force Base.
이거 보이시죠?
Okay, do you... do you see?
카메라에 모습이 찍히면
전세계로 방송되는걸 알겠죠
It happens
whenever he's on camera, whenever he knows the world
is watching... it's the same sequence over and over again.
똑같은 행동이
여러번 반복되고 있어요
A code of some kind. He's making contact, Saul.
일종의 암호로군
이미 접촉을 시도하고 있던거죠
누군가에게 메시지를 전달하고 있어요
He's sending a message to somebody... a handler,
참모라던가 잠복 요원이라던가
a sleeper cell, somebody.
더 알아볼 가치는 있군
We should explore this further.
암호해독부에 보내지
Let's get the crypto guys on it.
Pittman's team is the best... plus,
피트만의 팀이 최고예요
he knows how to be discreet.
게다가 일을 신중히
처리하는 편이죠
내가 연락해보지
I'll get his number.
저 여전히 철창행인가요?
So am I still going to jail?
아직은 아니지
Not just yet.
- 알고 싶은게 뭐죠?
- 그는 어떻게 죽었죠?
What do you want to know? How he died.
거기 있었나요? / 아뇨
Were you there? No.
- Did you ever meet him? - Abu Nazir?
- 만난 적은 있나요?
- 알부 나지르요?
당신을 심문한 사람 중에
그가 있었나요?
Was he ever present during any of your interrogations?
다시
Again. No, I never met him.
아뇨 만난 적 없어요
더 강하게
Harder.